JONATHAN HOLLINGER

232 TAYLOR DR · LEXINGTON, KY 40511 · (859) 552-5292 · <u>JONATHANMHOLLINGER@GMAIL.COM</u> https://jmhollinger.github.io/me

I am experienced in data warehousing, analysis, and solutions engineering. I help make data-driven decisions easy by deriving valuable insights from complex data and creating user experiences that short-circuit the path to finding answers when you need them.

EXPERIENCE

LEAD SOLUTIONS MANAGER

TOLEMI

August 2017 – Present

Managed new implementations of geospatial analytics platform.

- Connected disparate data sources from internal systems using SQL, PowerShell scripting, and other tools.
- Wrote SQL mappings to clean and transform data to standardized schema for use by analytics platform.
- Built analytics scoring models to help clients make data driven decisions.
- Wrote custom database functions to process data.

Provided key input to product development team.

- Supported requirements gathering for new products.
- Provided input on new UI/UX design processes.
- Gathered structured data on client use cases and needs to drive new product development.

Supported sales team with technical materials and guidance.

- Participated in client interactions to answer technical questions and provide guidance on ETL processes.
- Built demo sites start to finish using sample client data.
- Trained sales team on procurement processes, data sources, and other aspects of client interaction.

DIRECTOR OF PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CITY OF LEXINGTON, MAYOR'S OFFICE

December 2016 - August 2017

Managed the \$40M Town Branch Commons project.

- Secured \$14.1M federal TIGER grant for the project, the first ever for Lexington.
- Supported and advocated for the Town Branch Fund. Their efforts have raised over \$5M in private donations for the project.
- Secured <u>SCAPE Landscape Architecture</u> to complete their design vision for the project, and managed the masterplan design process.

Implemented process improvements using technology.

- Built framework to improve the special events permitting process.
- Developed project management dashboard to communicate project status to stakeholders.

SENIOR ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICER

CITY OF LEXINGTON, DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, PRESERVATION, AND DEVELOPMENT

December 2013 - December 2016

Managed projects and programs.

- Managed Lexington's vacant property program.
- Served as project manager for the Euclid Avenue Commercial Corridor Study and the Southland Drive Sidewalks project.
- Assisted with major technology implementations, including new systems for Permitting and Code Enforcement.

Worked with a variety of Divisions within the Department of Planning, Preservation, and Development on process improvements.

- Created new systems for tracking department information, including automated data extraction processes, data processing tools, and front-end interfaces.
- Created new ways for LFUCG's customers to contact city staff to improve response time and accuracy.
- Created replicable tools to clean city data in order to make it more useful for decision making.
- Created public engagement tools to collect and use data to drive project design. Specifically, on the <u>Southland Drive Sidewalks project</u>

Assisted with the day-to-day management of seven divisions of government.

- Assisted with financial management at the project and operational level.
- Directed the creation of policies and procedures to improve efficiency.
- Provided guidance to project managers on capital projects, including consultant selection and resolution of project issues.

LEGISLATIVE AIDE

CITY OF LEXINGTON, COUNCIL OFFICE

June 2010 - December 2013

Performed complex research regarding municipal government topics.

- Performed and presented extensive research on the Police and Fire Pension Fund, ultimately leading to landmark pension reform legislation in 2013.
- Researched and executed process improvements in several divisions of government, including the creation of improved forms for code enforcement actions and economic development agency reporting.

Provided staff support to the Council's budget process.

- Served as the primary staff person for Council budget review process in 2011, 2012, and 2013.
- Assembled documents and performed financial analysis of proposed budgets.

Served as the liaison for all residents, associations, and businesses in the 10th Council District

- Managed all constituent relations for the 10th District Council Office and presented information to the general public on LFUCG programs and projects.
- Created a custom database to track complaints, issues, and other contacts with the Council Office.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, MARTIN SCHOOL OF PUBLIC POLICY AND ADMINISTRATION

MASTER OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION

GPA: 3.90

August 2009 - May 2011

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, COLLEGE OF FINE ARTS

BACHELOR OF ARTS, ARTS ADMINISTRATION

GPA: 3.25

August 2005 - May 2009

SKILLS

- Microsoft Office Applications (Expert Level)
- Visual Basic for Applications
- SQL
- Statistical Research Methods and Software (SPSS, R)
- Node.js
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Python
- Geospatial (PostGIS, QGIS, ArcGIS)
- Cloud Services Configuration (AWS, Heroku)
- Google Analytics
- REST API Integrations

PUBLICATIONS

KENTUCKY PENSION REFORM UNDER SENATE BILL 2

KENTUCKY BENCH AND BAR, MARCH 2014

R. Douglas Martin, J.D. Chaney, Jonathan M. Hollinger

NEW ACCOUNTING STANDARDS FOR GOVERNMENT PENSIONS

KENTUCKY BENCH AND BAR, MARCH 2014

Lee Ann Watters, Jonathan M. Hollinger, and R. Douglas Martin

PUBLIC ART MASTER PLANNING FOR MUNICIPAL GOVERNMENTS: CORE COMPONENTS AND COMMON PRACTICES

UKNOWLEDGE - UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, 2011

Jonathan M. Hollinger

INTERESTS

Apart from my work with data, I am a proud fiancé to Jenifer, step-parent to four-year-old Bella, and dog-parent to three pups (Sadie, Tilly, and Oliver). I am also an avid remodeler of my 1950's cape cod in Lexington's Meadowthorpe neighborhood, as well as a woodworker, and artist.

I am also a self-taught web developer and enjoy building small web applications and working on open source tools that help bring transparency to government and provide governments, nonprofits, and citizens with tools to make smart, data-driven decisions.